<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Amanda Awadey</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on Amanda Awadey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Intended and Unintended Effects of an Additional Year in Senior High School</title><link>/blog/durationshs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/durationshs/</guid><description>The Intended and Unintended Effects of an Additional Year in Senior High School Ongoing, Columbia University In this paper, I investigate the effects of an additional year in senior high schools in Ghana on performance in the short term, and for college bound students, any persistent effects. This contributes to understanding the mechanisms of the established relationship between education and labor outcomes. Furthermore, changing the duration of senior high schools may have unintended impacts especially in environments where schooling is not free.</description></item><item><title>Towards a Cash-lite Economy: Mobile Money and Retail Payments</title><link>/blog/cashlite/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/cashlite/</guid><description>Towards a Cash-lite Economy: Mobile Money and Retail Payments Ongoing, Columbia University with Rowena Cornelius, Western University, Ontario Increased penetration of mobile phones, a large unbanked population coupled with the recent COVID-19 pandemic have advanced the rapid spread of mobile money usage in sub-Saharan Africa. Predominantly used for person-to-person transfers (P2P), mobile money is yet to gain significant traction as a mode of payment, particularly in retail. Empirically, evidence of the constraints and the factors that promote using mobile money as a payment tool is scant and was obtained before the COVID-19 pandemic.</description></item><item><title>Research</title><link>/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/about/</guid><description>Anticipating an Expected Increase in Crowding: Responses of Prospective College Applicants Ongoing, Columbia University Markets such as the education and labor market are disrupted periodically due to sudden swings in demand and supply and these may affect decision-making of economic agents. Precipitants of such disruptions include government policies, natural disasters, and pandemics. In the higher education market specifically, response margins may include forgoing or postponing a college degree and reconsideration of program/major choices affecting education attainment, which also impact labor market outcomes.</description></item></channel></rss>