<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research Work on Amanda Awadey</title><link>/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Research Work on Amanda Awadey</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Double the Number: High School Crowding and Schooling Outcomes</title><link>/blog/1jmp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/1jmp/</guid><description>Increased cohort size of labor supply entrants relative to labor demand generally results in adverse outcomes. Little is known, however, about the impact of an increased cohort size of entrants relative to education supply despite the close link between these markets. This is primarily because significant year-on-year changes in relative cohort size in education markets are rare. This paper shows its impact on performance and the college market by examining two reforms in Ghana that resulted in a significant increase in the 2013 high school graduating class.</description></item><item><title>The Intended and Unintended Effects of an Additional Year in High School</title><link>/blog/durationshs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/durationshs/</guid><description>The Intended and Unintended Effects of an Additional Year in Senior High School Ongoing, Columbia University Existing evidence posits that an additional year of schooling increases human capital on average. However, the extra year of education is usually associated with an increased breadth of the curriculum. In this paper, I investigate the effects of an additional year which increased the duration without a change in the curriculum. Particularly, the impact on performance in the short term and for college-bound students, any persistent effects.</description></item><item><title>Towards a Cash-lite Economy: Mobile Money and Retail Payments</title><link>/blog/cashlite/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/blog/cashlite/</guid><description>Increased penetration of mobile phones, a large unbanked population, and the recent COVID-19 pandemic have advanced the rapid spread of mobile money usage in sub-Saharan Africa. Predominantly used for person-to-person transfers (P2P), mobile money is yet to gain significant traction as a mode of payment, particularly in retail. Empirically, evidence of the constraints and the factors that promote using mobile money as a payment tool is scant and was obtained before the COVID-19 pandemic.</description></item></channel></rss>